Hi my name is Dean Hale and today I'm going to give you a general overview of how to play the American classic, poker.
Now different people think of poker as different games.
Today Texas hold 'em is probably the most popular game that people think of when they play poker.
But there are games that have stood the test of time such as five card draw, five card stud, Omaha, seven card stud, Omaha hi lo, the list goes on and on.
The essential thing you need to know to learn how to play poker is the starting value of each hand.
The starting value ranges from high card all the way to a royal flush and then there's the rankings in between.
High card is simply as it states, ace when you consider high card is listed as a high card.
The next ranking would be a pair, that would be any two cards that are of the same number.
The next ranking after that would be two pair, that would be two cards or four cards that have the same numerical value of the other one.
So I may have made that a little confusing, let's just say if you have two threes and two nines, that would be two pair.
So it's two cards the same number and another two cards of the same number, that's two pair.
The next after that would be three of a kind or what some people call a set.
A set would simply be three cards of the same number in your hand.
After three of a kind would be a straight.
A straight is any five cards in sequential order of different suits.
After a straight you would have a flush.
A flush is five cards of the same suit whether it be hearts, diamonds, spades or clubs in a non-sequential order.
After a flush, the next highest hand value would be called a full house or what some poker players refer to as a boat.
And that is simply three cards of the same number and then two cards of the same number.
So for instance the best full house you could have would be three aces and two kings, that would be called aces over kings.
After a full house you would have four of a kind, simply as it states, you have four cards of the same number.
The two hands that beat four of a kind would be a straight flush or a royal flush.
A royal flush is ten, jack, queen, king, ace in order of the same suit and that is the best hand in poker.
My name is Dean Hale and I just taught you the basics on how to play poker.